Preliminary Guide to the H. Keith H. Brodie, Chancellor, Records, 1970 - 1985
Duke University. University Archives
H. Keith H. Brodie, Chancellor, records 1970 - 1985
Brodie, H. Keith H. (Harlow Keith Hammond), 1939-
34.5 linear feet, Extent: 23,000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
H. Keith H. Brodie came to Duke in 1974 as professor and chairman of the Department of Psychiatry and director of Psychiatric Services at Duke University Medical Center. Dr. Brodie served as Duke's Chancellor from 1982 to 1985 and as Duke's President from 1985 to 1993. Collection includes university administrative records, personal papers, manuscripts, photographs, printed matter, memorabilia, and other material created or received by Dr. Brodie during his tenure as Chancellor, 1982-1985. Subjects include admissions, the Academic Council, alumni, committees and campaigns, athletics, The Duke Endowment, various university departments, the Medical Center, and Student Affairs. English.
UA.06.53.0001
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The H. Keith H. Brodie, Chancellor, Records was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1993.
Biographical Note
H. Keith H. Brodie received his M.D. in 1965 from Columbia University. He served at hospitals in New Orleans and New York City before becoming a clinical associate with the National Institute of Mental Health in 1968. In 1970, he joined the medical faculty of Stanford University. He came to Duke in 1974 as professor and chairman of the Department of Psychiatry and director of Psychiatric Services at Duke University Medical Center. Dr. Brodie served as Duke's Chancellor from 1982 to 1985 and as Duke's President from 1985 to 1993.
Collection Overview
Collection includes university administrative records, personal papers, manuscripts, photographs, printed matter, memorabilia, and other material created or received by Dr. Brodie during his his tenure as Chancellor, 1982-1985. Subjects include admissions, the Academic Council, alumni, committees and campaigns, athletics, The Duke Endowment, various university departments, the Medical Center, and Student Affairs.
Subject Headings
Brodie, H. Keith H. (Harlow Keith Hammond), 1939-; Duke Endowment; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. Medical Center; Duke University. Chancellor; Education, Higher -- North Carolina -- History; Universities and colleges -- North Carolina -- History -- 20th century
Contents of Collection
- Subject Files, 1970-1985 and undated.
  - A, General, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - A. B. Duke Scholarships, 1982 July-1985 (Box 1)
  - AAMIS (Academic Administration Management Information System), 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Academic Calendar, 1982 July-1985 (Box 1)
  - Academic Computing Advisory Committee, 1982 July-1984 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council: Christie Report on Nature and Role of Academic Council, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council: Dr. Lewin, Chairman (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council Committee on University Governance, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council Minutes (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 1)
  - Academic Facilities: Dr. Ward, Assistant Provost, 1982 July–1985 April (Box 1)
  - (Box 1)
  - Academic Rankings, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Academic Systems, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Accounting Dept., General, 1982 July-1984 June (Box 1)
  - Adcock, John F., University Controller, 1982 July-1985 June (Box 1)
  - Administrative Systems Advisory Council, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Administrators Returning to Faculty Positions, 1982 July (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Alexander Report, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Admissions Office: Dr. Cahow, 1982 July-1984 October (Box 1)
  - Admissions Office: Inquiries Concerning Applicants, 1982 July-1985 June (Box 1)
  - Admissions, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Miscellaneous, 1982-1985 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: North Carolina Applicants, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Admissions: University Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Admissions Office: Dr. Scott, Director, 1982 July-1985 June (Box 2)
  - Admissions Planning Meeting, 1984 May 22 (Box 2)
  - Aging: Center for Aging and Human Development, 1982 July-1985 May (Box 2)
  - Aircraft Services, 1982 July (Box 2)
  - Alumni Affairs: Field Activities, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Affairs: Grads, 1982 July-1985 May (Box 2)
  - Alumni Affairs: Miscellaneous (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Affairs: Search Committee for Director, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Register, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Speech Material, undated (Box 2)
  - Alumni Travel, 1982 July-1985 (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - American Dance Festival, 1977-1985 (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Norman G. (Human Protein Index), 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Anthropology, Department of, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
  - Applications: Administrative and Teaching Positions, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - Appointment, Promotion and Tenure Committee, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - Apte, Mahadev L., 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - Annual Giving, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Archives (University Archives), 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Archives (University Archives), 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Art, Department of (Ann Epstein), 1983-1985 (Box 3)
  - Art, Department of, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
  - Art Museum, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Cannon Mills (Max Messner), undated (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Charlotte Prospects, undated (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Chicago, undated (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Dallas, undated (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: New York Prospects, undated (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: R. J. Reynolds, undated (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Washington, D.C. Prospects, undated (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign (Joel Fleishman) (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Budget, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Faculty Searches: Budget Projections, etc., 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Associated Students of Duke University (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign, 1981 Oct.-1982 July (Box 3)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Executive Committee, 1983-1984 June 30 (Box 4)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Executive Committee, 1984 July 1-1985 June 30 (Box 4)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Foundations, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: H. Keith Brodie, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Miscellaneous (2 folders), 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Arts and Sciences Campaign: Steering Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
  - Arts, Institute of the, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (2 folders), 1982-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Atlantic Coast Conference, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Atlantic Coast Conference, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Basketball, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Budget, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Club Sports, 1982-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: College Football Association, 1982 July-1983 Jan. (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Concerned Iron Dukes Association, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Director (Tom Butters), 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Fencing, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Football, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Miscellaneous (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: NCAA (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Pye Report on the Financing of Athletics, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: Pye Report on Financing Athletics (and related documents), 1970-1984 (Box 5)
  - Athletics: Swimming, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Athletics: Women's Intercollegiate Athletics (Title IX), 1982-1984 (Box 5)
  - AT&T Bell Labs, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - B, General, 1982-1985 (Box 5)
  - Baligh, Helmy, 1979-1983 (Box 5)
  - Bates, Margaret, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Battle, Joseph, 1982-1985 (Box 5)
  - Bevan, William, Provost, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Bindewald, Richard A.: Special Assistant to Chancellor, August 1983-1981 (Box 5)
  - Black Affairs, President's Council on, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
  - Black Faculty Search (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 5)
  - Black Faculty, Committee on, (Maxwell), 1982-1984 (Box 5)
  - Black Students: Reports, Questionnaires, etc., 1982-1984 (Box 5)
  - Blackburn Fund, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Blaydon, C. C.: Academic Policy and Planning, 1982-83 (Box 5)
  - Blue Cross-Blue Shield, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Board of Visitors (Crossland Report), 1983 (Box 5)
  - Bookstores, 1982-1984 (Box 5)
  - Botany, Department of, 1982-1985 (Box 5)
  - British American Festival (2 folders), 1981-1984 (Box 5)
  - Brodie Research Fund: Budget, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Bryan Center, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Budget: Chancellor's Discretionary Fund (Reiber 399-1071) (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 5)
  - Budget: Chancellor's Scholarship Fund, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Budget (4 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 5)
  - Mary Duke Biddle Foundation, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Chancellor Scholarship Fund 168-1400, 1976-1983 (Box 6)
  - Budget Forecast, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Budgets and Measurements Office, Harrison Brooke, Director, 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - Burroughs Corporation (Paul Stern), 1985 (Box 6)
  - Bursar's Office, 1982-1984 (Box 6)
  - C, General, 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - CALICO, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Campus Services, 1982 July (Box 6)
  - Canadian Studies, 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - Card Gym, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Chairmen (Department): Salary Supplements, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Chapel, 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - Chemistry, Department of (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - China Exchange Program, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Classics, Department of, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Clotfelter, Charles, Vice Provost for Academic Policy and Planning (2 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Cole, R. Taylor, 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - COLOE (3 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Commencement, 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - Commonwealth Fund, 1982-1984 (Box 6)
  - Comparative Literature, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Computation Center, 1982-1986 (Box 6)
  - Computer Science, Department of: Donald Rose, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - Computer Science, Department of (2 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Computer Software, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Computing: Duke/UNC Proposal to NSF, undated (Box 7)
  - COFHE (Consortium on Financing Higher Education) (3 folders), 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - COTH (Council of Teaching Hospitals) Endowment Fund, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Continuing Education, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Continuing Education, Annual Reports (2 folders), 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Convex Computer Corporation, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
  - Cost Sharing (Grants), 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Counsel (Office of University Counsel, Eugene McDonald) (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - CAPS (Counseling and Psychological Services), 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Cresap, McCormick, and Paget (Compensation Studney RE: Senior Admin.), 1981-1984 (Box 7)
  - Crossland, Fred (Program in Education), 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Cultural Affairs, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
  - D, General, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Data Processing: Jay Roussueav, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Dean Search (TCAS), 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Dean's Council, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Development: Barbara Smith, Associate Director, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Development: Budget Review, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Development: Long Range Planning Report (David Ross), 1979 (Box 7)
  - Development Office: Annual Fund, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Development: President's Associates, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Development: Reports: Individual, Corporate, Foundation Proposals Pending, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Development: Reports: Private Gifts, Grants, and Contracts, 1982-1984 (Box 8)
  - Development Office: Corporate, Foundations, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Development Office: Gift Records, 1982-1984 (Box 8)
  - Development Office: Gift Records, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Development Office: Planned Giving (Ralph McCaughan, Director), 1982-1983 (Box 8)
  - Development office: Special Programs, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Development officers, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Development Support Services, (Paul Robins, Director), 1983-1985 (Box 8)
  - Development: Misc. Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Development: Trustee Committee for Institutional Advancement 1982-1983 (Box 8)
  - Dining Halls, 1983-1985 (Box 8)
  - Divinity School (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Dormitory (Proposed) (4 folders), 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Drama, 1982-1984 (Box 8)
  - Drug Science Foundation, 1982-1984 (Box 8)
  - Duke, Doris, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Duke Endowment: Indenture and Deed of Trust (1924), 1980 (Box 8)
  - Duke Endowment: Misc. Correspondence and (NC/SC Student Scholarships), 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Duke Endowment: Misc. Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
  - Duke Endowment: Proposal (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Duke Endowment: Anniversary Planning, 1983 (Box 8)
  - The Duke Endowment and Duke University: A Joint Statement by Thomas L. Perkins and President Terry Sanford, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Duke Endowment: Reports on Appropriations, 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - Duke Endowment Proposal, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Duke Endowment Proposal, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Durham, City of, 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - E, General, 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - East Campus, 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - East-West Expressway (Crest Street Community Relocation), 1978-1982 (Box 9)
  - East-West Expressway, July 1982 (Box 9)
  - Economics Department (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - Education Program (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - Emeriti Professors, 1982-1984 (Box 9)
  - Employee Health Benefits, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Endowment Funds, 1982-1984 (Box 9)
  - Energy Problems, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Engineering School (10 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 9)
  - English Department, 1982-1984 (Box 9)
  - English Department, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Executive Health Program, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Executive Officers Retreat (3 folders), 1985 (Box 10)
  - F, General, 1982-1985 (Box 10)
  - FAC Committee on Flexible Retirement Plan: Ad Hoc Committee on Implementation, 1982-1984 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Benefits, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Commons, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Compensation Committee (5 folders), 1979-1985 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Leave Policy, 1980-1982 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Salaries, 1982-1985 (Box 10)
  - Federal Relations Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Federal Relations, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - FIDIA Neurobiology Institute, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Financial Aid: Dr. Cahow, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Financial Aid: Draft Registration, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - Financial Aid: Federal Programs, 1982-1985 (Box 10)
  - Financial Aid: General 1985-1985 (Box 10)
  - Financial Aid: Student Loan Office, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Fish, Stanley: Tompkins, Jane Review, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Forceps Group, 1982-1984 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation, 1980-1985 (Box 10)
  - Forestry History Society, 1983-1985 (Box 10)
  - Forestry, School of (SFES) (5 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - Founders' Society, 1982-1984 (Box 11)
  - Fowlie, Wallace (Roman Catholic Chapel Proposal), 1982-1984 (Box 11)
  - Fraternities, Sororities, Living Groups, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Freshmen (Freshmen Orientation), 1985 (Box 11)
  - Friedl, Dr. Ernestine (Dean, TCAS), 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - Fringe Benefits, 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - Fukuhara, Dr. Nobukazu, 1978-1983 (Box 11)
  - Fuller, J. Peyton: (Flexible Benefits), 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - Fuqua School of Business (5 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - Fuqua School of Business: Building Program, 1980-1982 (Box 11)
  - Fuqua School of Business: Keller Review Committee, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Fuqua School of Business: Arie Lewin: Air Force Contract, 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Geology, Department of, 1983-1985 (Box 11)
  - German, Department of, 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - Government Relations, Office of, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Governship and State Planning (Governors Center), 1983-1985 (Box 11)
  - Graduate School: Craufurd Goodwin, 1980-1985 (Box 11)
  - Graduate School: Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1982-1984 (Box 12)
  - Graduate School: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
  - Graduate Student Instructors: Statistics, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Graduate and Professional Student Council: Minutes, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Greater Durham Community Foundation, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
  - Griffiths, Philip (2 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 12)
  - H, General, 1982 July-1985 (Box 12)
  - Hamner, Clay, 1982 July-1985 (Box 12)
  - Hanks, Nancy: Endowment for the Arts, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Harward, S. C., 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Health, Physical Education, and Recreation, Department of (HPER), 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Henderson, R. James, 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Card Gym, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Health Care Costs Plan, undated (Box 12)
  - Higher Education and National Affairs, 1982 (Box 12)
  - History, Department of, (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - History, Department of (2 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 12)
  - Homesites, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Housing: Students, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Huestis, Charles B. (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Human Development (University Program in Human Development) (2 folders), 1981-1985 (Box 12)
  - Human Resources: Labor Relations, 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Human Resources, 1982-1984 (Box 12)
  - I, General, 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - IBM, 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - Inauguration: H. Keith H. Brodie, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Incentives for Fund Raising, 1977-1978 (Box 13)
  - Incentives for Fund Raising, 1982-1984 (Box 13)
  - Industry: University Relations, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Infirmary, 1983-1985 (Box 13)
  - Insurance, 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Internal Audit, 1982-1984 (Box 13)
  - International Studies (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - Investment Committee (6 folders), 1978-1985 (Box 13)
  - Investment Options for Employees 1983 (Box 13)
  - Islamic and Arabian Development Studies, 1983-1985 (Box 13)
  - ITT, 1984 (Box 13)
  - J, General, 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - K, General, 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - Kahr, Toby (Director of Human Resources), 1983-1985 (Box 13)
  - Kaiser Permanente, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Kaludis (George Kaludis Associates, Management Consultants), 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Kreps, Dr. Juanita, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - L, General, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - Lake Tanganika Project, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Langford, Dr. Thomas, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Latent Image, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Law School (5 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - Law School Building, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Leadership Program, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Library, 1982 July-1983 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Library, 1983 July (Box 14)
  - Library Council, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Library: Triangle Research Libraries Network, 1980-1984 (Box 14)
  - Librarians: Tuition Benefits, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Library Review: External (Dr. Keith Brodie), 1983 (Box 14)
  - University Librarian Search Committee 1984 (Box 14)
  - Local Area Network Task Force: Report, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Lord Corporation (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - Luce, Henry Foundation, 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - M, General, 1983-1985 (Box 15)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - MacDonald, Eugene (Vice President for Administration), 1985 (Box 15)
  - MacDonald, Susan, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Marine Laboratory (DUML) (2 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 15)
  - Marshall, Roger (University Secretary), 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - Master of Arts in Liberal Studies (MALS), 1982-1984 (Box 15)
  - Material Support Division, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Mathematics, Department of 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - Mellon Foundation, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - Memberships in Professional Organizations, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - Methodist (United Methodist Church), 1983-1985 (Box 15)
  - Minority Affairs, Office of, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Mortgages (Faculty), 1980-1984 (Box 15)
  - Music, Department of (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - N, General, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities, 1985 (Box 15)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
  - National Humanities Center, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - National Science Foundation, 1983-1985 (Box 15)
  - Neurobiology Program, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Nisbet, Caroline, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Nixon Library, 1981-1983 (Box 15)
  - North Carolina Association of Independent Colleges and Universities, 1982-1985 (Box 15)
  - North Carolina Biotechnology Center, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - North Carolina Board of Science and Technology (3 folders), 1982-1984 (Box 15)
  - North Carolina School of Science and Mathematics, 1982-1983 (Box 16)
  - North Carolina State University, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - North Carolina, University of, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Nuclear Magnetic Resonance, 1982-1983 (Box 16)
  - 0, General, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Officers Executive Committee (including Retreat Materials), 1985 (Box 16)
  - Ombudsman, 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Opportunity Development Center (5 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Opportunity Development Center: Human Resources Relationship (Burke-Johnston), 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - P, General (Duke-University of Paris Exchange and Presidential Award Program 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Patents (2 folders), 1979-1985 (Box 16)
  - Pew Memorial Trust, 1983-1985 (Box 16)
  - Philosophy, Department of, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Peat, Marwick, Mitchell, 1982 (Box 16)
  - Pinnell, Doren (Carnegie Grant Proposal), 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Carnegie Corporation: Grant Proposal, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Physical Plant Department, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Physics, Department of, 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Phytotron, 1982 (Box 16)
  - Piva, John J., Vice President for Alumni Affairs and Development (3 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Policies, University, 1982-1984 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Policy Sciences and Public Affairs (4 folders), 1977-1985 (Box 17)
  - Political Science, Department of (2 folders), 1982-1985 (Box 17)
  - Powe, Porter, and Alphin, 1982 July (Box 17)
  - Journal of Health Politics, Policy and Law, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - Presidential Search Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - President's House, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Primate Center, 1982-1985 (Box 17)
  - Duke School for Children (Duke Preschool and Primary Program), 1982-1984 (Box 17)
  - Duke University Press: The Journals Press, 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - Duke University Press General Correspondence and Reports (2 folders), 1979-1985 (Box 17)
  - Duke University Press: Editorial Advisory Board, 1979-1983 (Box 17)
  - Duke University Press: Editorial Advisory Board, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - Distinguished Professorships: Advisory Committee (7 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 17)
  - Provost's Planning Retreat 1984 June 12-1984 June 13 (Box 18)
  - Psychological Services Center, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Psychology, Department of, 1982-1985 (Box 18)